The day terror went live.
September 5 is a thriller, drama, history film directed by Tim Fehlbaum.
During the 1972 Munich Olympics, an American sports broadcasting crew finds itself
thrust into covering the hostage crisis involving Israeli athletes.
Roone Arledge, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
Geoffrey Mason, played by John Magaro.
Marvin Bader, played by Ben Chaplin.
Marianne Gebhardt, played by Leonie Benesch.
Jacques Lesgards, played by Zinedine Soualem.
Gladys Deist, played by Georgina Rich.
September 5 is a 2024 German historical drama thriller film
directed, co-written, and produced by Tim Fehlbaum.
The ensemble cast includes Peter Sarsgaard, John
Magaro, Ben Chaplin, and Leonie Benesch.
The film chronicles the Munich massacre of 1972 from the perspective of
the ABC Sports crew and their coverage of the events.
It premiered at the 81st Venice International Film Festival on 29 August 2024,
and was released in Germany by Constantin Film on 9 January 2025.
September 5 received positive reviews from critics and won
several accolades, including nine Lolas.
The film also received nominations for Best Original Screenplay at the 97th Academy
Awards, and Best Motion Picture – Drama at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of palestinian-israeli conflict,
olympic games, 1970s, journalism, munich, germany.
The tone is emotional and intense.